In the future, intelligence is extinct.
Idiocracy is a comedy, science fiction, adventure film directed by Mike Judge.
To test its top-secret Human Hibernation Project, the Pentagon picks the most average Americans it can find - an
Army private and a prostitute - and sends them to the year 2505 after a series of freak events.
But when they arrive, they find a civilization so
dumbed-down that they're the smartest people around.
Joe Bauers, played by Luke Wilson.
Rita, played by Maya Rudolph.
Frito, played by Dax Shepard.
President Camacho, played by Terry Crews.
Secretary of Defense, played by Anthony 'Citric' Campos.
Secretary of State, played by David Herman.
Idiocracy is a 2006 American science fiction comedy film co-produced and directed by Mike Judge
from a screenplay written by Judge and Etan Cohen based on a story written by Judge.
The plot follows United States Army librarian Joe Bauers and prostitute
Rita, who undergo a government hibernation experiment.
Joe and Rita awake five hundred years later in a
dystopian anti-intellectual society.
The cast includes Luke Wilson, Maya Rudolph, Dax Shepard, Terry Crews,
David Herman, Justin Long, Andrew Wilson, and Brad Jordan.
The concept of Idiocracy dates back to a concept Judge envisioned in 1996.
Judge finished a script with the working title 3001 in
2001, rewriting the film a year later.
Filming took place throughout 2004 at Austin Studios and other cities in Texas.
Idiocracy serves as a social satire that touches on issues including anti-intellectualism,
commercialism, consumerism, dysgenics, voluntary childlessness, and overpopulation.
20th Century Fox was hesitant to promote the film, refusing to grant it a
wide release, and did not screen the film for critics.
The decision not to market Idiocracy was seen as unexpected, following the
success of Office Space (1999), and led to speculation.
According to Crews, the film's satirical depiction of corporations made the film financially unviable, while Judge attributed 20th Century Fox's decision to negative
test screenings; Judge stated that 20th Century Fox believed that the film would develop a cult following through its DVD release, similar to Office Space.
The film was released in the United States on September 1, 2006.
Despite its lack of a major theatrical release, which resulted in a $495,000 gross at the box
office, the film received positive reviews from critics and has since become a cult film.
The film explores themes of future, army, prostitute, usa president, congress.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and thought_provoking.